Collection of Ephemera Relating to the Marketing of Books, 1742-2014: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Publishing Ephemera With Uncertain Dates, portions of 12 boxes
  - A monumental achievement and historical undertaking, undated; portion of 1 box
    Broadside folded into 8-sided pamphlet. With examples of pages and announcements for related merchandise. Also lists exhibition dates.
  - [postcard], undated; portion of 1 box
    Broadside with a color photo of an illustrator working. Blank on verso.
  - Saint john's bible heritage edition, undated; portion of 1 box
    Folder with information about the publication. 8 1/2x11 sheet showing which of the 360 sets will be available for purchase and which will be reserved for benefactors. There is also a stapled stack of color printouts with information about the Heritage Edition and its completion schedule.
  - Manuale tipografico, undated; portion of 1 box
    Franco Maria Ricci?
    Advertisement for a 900 copy reprint of the Manuale tipografico.
  - What katy did: in recognition of feminism in the american experience, undated; portion of 1 box
    Santa Barbara, California: Randall House
    Bifolium. Illustrated with pictures of covers of the books in the catalogue.
  - Go west, young woman, undated; portion of 1 box
    New York, NY: Rostenberg & Stern
    Broadside. Avertises facsimile reprints of 19th-century travel accounts by American women.
  - Business card of Fr. Eric Hollas, OSB, undated; portion of 1 box
    Bifolium business card of Fr. Eric Hollas, OSB, Senior Associate for Arts and Cultural Affairs at Saint John's. Front cover has a red background and a photograph of a madonna and child statue.
  - When harry met marion, undated; portion of 1 box
    Smith's Bookshop Limited
    Advertisement for a biography og Harry Emmet. Printed on a magenta piece of 8 1/2x11 paper.
  - Art for the new collector III: re-emerging american artists., undated; portion of 1 box
    New York, NY: Spanierman Gallery, LLC
    In original envelope addressed to Mr. and Mrs. Laurence Mcgilvery/Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America. Broadside press release and a list of works that can be viewed in the gallery and online. 4 double-sided Broadsides and one one-sided Broadside with integral order form.
  - Zapf, Hermann: Zapf Hermann and his design philosophy, undated; portion of 1 box
    Chicago, IL: STA-HZ
    Bifolium, ripped apart at the spine and now in two pieces. Includes integral order form and integral STA membership form. Addressed to Emerson Wulling.
  - Star bookworks, undated; portion of 1 box
    Apache Junction, AZ: Starr Bookworks
    Four-sided pamphlet. Has photos of the bindings available from the bindery.
  - The art of publishers' bookbindings 1815-1915, undated; portion of 1 box
    Los Angeles, CA: William Dailey Rare Books Ltd
    Bifolium printed in color. The first 100 copies numbered and signed by the author.
  - Maret, Russell and Annie Schlecter: Swan & Hoop 2: a roman inscription, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Maret, Russell and Annie Schlecter
    New York, NY: Russell Maret
    Postcard illustrated with photos. Blank on one side.
  - Maret, Russell: Swan & Hoop 1: mediaeval in padua, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Maret, Russell
    Postcard with photos of the publication on one side.
  - Gehl, Paul F.: Swan & Hoop 3: a meditation in rome, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Gehl, Paul F.
    Postcard with photos of the publication on one side. Book has an essay by Russell Maret and photographs by Annie Schlecter.
  - A Specimen of an Etymological Dictionary Attributed to John Mitchell Kemble, undated; 2 copies
    Rulon-Miller Books
    2 sheets, one with an announcement of the publication of the recently-discovered manuscript and a page with a sample entry.
  - Thoreau, Henry David: Wild fruits, undated; portion of 1 box
    Concord, MA: Thoreau Society
    Broadside with color information on front, book information on verso.
  - New webster's international encyclopedia, undated; portion of 1 box
    Trident Press International
    2-fold color pamphlet with order form laid in.
  - Moser, Barry: No shortcuts: an essay on wood engraving, undated; portion of 1 box
    Iowa City, Iowa: University of Iowa Center for the Book
    Folded Broadside. Previously folded and mailed to Robert Rulon-Miller. Limited edition with a limited number of copies available unbound. Announcement also has discount schedule.
  - Browne, Michael Dennis and Patricia Hempl: 2 for 5, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Browne, Michael Dennis and Patricia Hempl
    Six-sided pamphet printed in blue and black. Invitation to the publication party laid in. Iintegral order form.
  - Geriadur Prifysgol cymru (a dictionary of the welsh language), undated; portion of 1 box
    Cardiff, Wales, UK: University of Wales Press (Gwasg Prifysgol Cymru)
    Six-sided pamphlet in English and Welsh. Sample page with bilingual explanations. Integral bilingual order form.
  - Printed catalogues of french book auctions and sales by private treaty 1643-1830 in the library of the grolier club, undated; portion of 1 box
    Northhampton, Massachusetts: Veatchs Arts of the Book
    Broadside advertising a sale catalogue of french libraries. Printed on one side only.
  - Pinsky, Robert: Shirt, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Pinsky, Robert
    Winnetka, IL: Vixen Press
    Bifolium. Edition size written in red pen inside. The book has a forword by Louise Glück.
  - Dunnigan, Brian Leigh: Frontier metropolis: picturing early detroit, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Dunnigan, Brian Leigh
    Detroit, Michigan: Wayne State University Press
    Color catalogue with scaled-down sample pages.
  - American heritage dictionary software, undated; portion of 1 box
    Writing Tools Group
    Broadside printed in blue and black. Offers both Deluxe Third Edition and Third Standard Edition. Integral order form.
  - Rumphius, Georgius Everhardus: The ambrose herbal, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Rumphius, Georgius Everhardus
    UK: Yale Books
    Bifolium with scaled-down sample pages. With a description of the book and quotes from critics.
  - Pollak, Oliver B.: A year at the sorbonne, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Pollak, Oliver B.
    Bifolium pamplet with sample page laid in. Small piece of paper with a list of dealer discounts pasted to the bottom of the second page.
  - "Happy in my stomach", undated; portion of 1 box
    YMCA Refugee and Rehabilitation Services
    Piece of paper folded into 6-sided pamphlet. Detachable order form and sample recipe for stewed chicked with pineapple sauce. Cookbook published to raise money for the YMCA Refugee and Rehabilitation Services.
  - Chopin, Fryderyk: Early european maps of japan, undated; portion of 1 box
    Author: Chopin, Fryderyk
    Bifolium with the majority of text in Japanese. Includes thumbnail-size samples of the maps. Title and contact information are bilingual.
  - Chopin, Fryderyk: Piano concerto No. 2 in F minor, op. 21, undated; 2 copies
    Bifolium. Announcement of a facsimile edition of Chopin's Piano Concerto No. 2
  - Bhutan, undated; portion of 1 box
    Cambridge, MA: Friendly Planet
    Large bifolium. Limited edition offered to patrons who make a donation of $10.000. Book is recognized by Guinness World Records as the world's largest boo (5x7 feet).
  - Verbatim the language quarterly, undated; portion of 1 box
    Essex, Connecticut: Verbatim
    Large Broadside advertising the periodical printed on cardboard. Brown lettering on beige. Verso blank.
- 32101080849431 (Box B-000869)
- 32101080849449 (Box B-000870)
- 32101080849456 (Box B-000871)
- 32101080849464 (Box B-000872)
- 32101080849472 (Box B-000873)
- 32101080849480 (Box B-000874)
- 32101080849498 (Box B-000875)
- 32101080849506 (Box B-000876)
- 32101080849514 (Box B-000877)
- 32101080849522 (Box B-000878)
- 32101080849530 (Box P-000071)
- 32101080849548 (Box P-000072)
- 32101080849555 (Box P-000073)
- 32101080849563 (Box P-000074)
- 32101080849571 (Box Z-000004)